Guide to the Ford Madox Ford collection, [ca. 1850]-1973
Ford, Ford Madox collection,
- Series III. Incoming correspondence and manuscripts by others
  - A-B
    - [Boluls?] to Alfred William Hunt, Mar.28, 1861; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 15)
      Yorkshire; My Dear Sir, I will take the picture; please finish it as carefully as possible
    - Bonelli, Jacques ALS to Bartolome & Signor Lionisi, May 24, 1880; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 16)
      [Corsica?] Caro Bartolome, e Signor Lionisi / Vengo per darvi il buon giorno a tuta due; come pure per avertirvi di darme
    - Boni, Albert & Charles, Inc. DS [Ford Statements of Account], [1927-1931]; 50 leaves (Box 49, Folder 17)
      New York; [More than 50 statements of Ford account]
    - Boni, Alber & Charles, Inc. TL[printed] Press Release, Apr.6, 1926; 2 leaves (Box 49, Folder 17.1)
      New York; Publicity Notes from Albert & Charles Boni: "A Confession from Ford Madox Ford"
    - Removed (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Boni, Albert & Charles, Inc. TLS to Ford, Feb.25, 1926; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 19)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: We have worked very hard on promotion work and sales on NO MORE PARADES [Signed Charles Boni, Jr.]
    - Boni, Albert & Charles, Inc. TL[copy to Arthur B. Spingarn, Jun.6, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 19.5)
      New York; Dear Sir: We have your letter of June 3rd in reference to the cancellation of Mr. Ford Madox Ford's contract [Signed Charles Boni, Jr.]
    - Boni & Liveright TLS to Ford, Dec.1, 1926; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 19.6)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I am sending you a set of proofs of Mr. Pound's "Collected Poems" [Signed T.R. Smith] [Julian Loewe papers]
    - Boni & Liveright TLS to Ford, Jun.15, 1927; 2 leaves (Box 49, Folder 20)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I am enclosing herewith our check for $300 as sthe first monthly payment [Signed Donald D. Friede]
    - Boni & Liveright TLS to Ford, Jul.6, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 21)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: Sorry for the delay on this check. Through an oversight I had not placed your contract [Signed Donald S. Friede]
    - Boni & Liveright TLS to Ford, Nov.11, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 22)
      New York; Dear Ford: No, I have not received the check, and nobody here has seen it [Signed Donald S. Friede]
    - Boni & Liveright TLS to Ford, Nov.18, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 23)
      New York; Dear Ford: I should have acknowledged your check before this, and I apologize [Signed Donald S. Friede]
    - Boni & Liveright TL[copy] to Arthur B. Spingarn, Jul.25, 1927; 2 leaves (Box 49, Folder 24)
      New York; Dear Mr. Spingarn: We have gone into every possible angle of the Ford-Boni-Boni & Liveright contract [Signed Donald S. Friede]
    - Boni & Liveright TL[copy] to Arthur B. Spingarn, Jul.27, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 25)
      New York; Dear Mr. Spingarn: After carefully considering the Ford Madox Ford situation [Signed Donald S. Friede]
    - Boodle, Walter T. AL[extract,copy] to J. B. Pinker, Jul.3, 1911; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 26)
      London; My dear Pinker: ... I have no hesitation whatever in advising you to have absolutely nothing to say [Entire letter in the Huntington Library]
    - The Bookman TLS to Ford, Jan.7, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 27)
      New York; My dear Ford: I should like very much to have that part of your introduction to "The Sisters" [Signed Burton Rascoe (Editor)]
    - Boots Booklovers Library TLS to G. Hueffer, Nov.14, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 28)
      London; Dear Sir, With reference to your application for a secondhand copy of "Ethics in the Future" [Signed F. Richardson, Head Librarian]
    - Borschitzky, G.T. ALS to Elsie Martindale Hueffer, Dec.31, 1893; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 49, Folder 29)
      London; Dear Miss Elsie/ Allow me to reach to you a sermon, today being Sunday:-
    - Bosanquet, Alys TL[copy]S to Violet Hunt, [1899?]; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 30)
      London; Dear Miss Hunt, I saw Mr. C[rawfurd] and told him I had met you in Paris, [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Bosanquet, Alys TL[fragment]S to Violet Hunt, [1899?]; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 31)
      Yorkshire; I don't see that anything is changed in that way. [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Boughton, George Henry ALS to Margaret R. Hunt (Mrs. A.W.0, [n.d.]; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 32)
      London; Dear Mrs. Hunt/ Many thanks for your kind not of invitation. [Violet Hunt papers] [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Boughton, George Henry ALS to Violet Hunt, Jan.23, 1884; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 49, Folder 33)
      London; My dear Miss Violet/ It was very naughty of you to strip the very gloves from your generous hands [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Boughton, George Henry ALS to Violet Hunt, May 30, 1885; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 49, Folder 34)
      London; Dear Miss Violetta/ Thanks for your sweet and kind letter from us both [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Boughton, George Henry ALS to Violet Hunt, Sept.11, 1885; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 49, Folder 35)
      Kirriemuir, Scotland; DV/ It was most kind and sweet of you and Venice to look after [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Boughton, George Henry ALS to Violet Hunt, Sept.19, 1886; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 49, Folder 36)
      Kent; Dear {a violet blossom] You young "story"! The members day to varnish is not on Wednesday [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Boughton, George Henry ALS to Violet Hunt, Sept.1, 1886; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 37)
      Scotland; D. O. V./ Got your letter as I went through St. Marys Home this morning. [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Boughton, George Henry ALS to Violet Hunt, Sept.10, 1886; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 49, Folder 38)
      Scotland; D.V. (The O. meant "old"! I got your note all right and the paper but I blush to say [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Boughton, George Henry ALS to Violet Hunt, Sept.15, 1889; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 39)
      Suffolk, D V/ I did not reply and thank you for your interest arrent the picture [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Boughton, George Henry ALS to Violet Hunt, Oct.25, 1895; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 40)
      [London] D V/ It was most sweet of you to send me an early copy [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Bourret, J. ALS to Violet Hunt, Feb.6, 1933; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 49, Folder 41)
      Paris; Chere Madame, J'ai bien recu le livre "The Wife of Rossetti" que vour m'avez envoye. [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Bowen, Elizabeth ALS to Violet Hunt, Jan.26, [n.y.]; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 42)
      Oxford; Dear Mrs. Hueffer/ Thank you so very much for your kind invitation - Alas, I cannot
    - Bower, Warren TLS to Ford, Sept.18, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 43)
      New York; My dear Mr. Ford: i have received a letter from Mr. Palmer, the present editor
    - Bowers, Thomas envelope, Sept.24, 1818; 1 envelope (Box 49, Folder 44)
      Darlington; Thos. Bowers [Envelope addressed to Bowers]
    - Brad[?], A. G. ALS to George Peacock, Jan.30, 1837; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 45)
      [n.p.] My dear Sir/ The accompanying documents are not addressed to me but Capt. Beaufort has allowed me to take [Written inside and ALS from Dominique Francois Jean Arago to Captain Francis Beaufort which has written inside an ALS to Edward Ellice from Arago] [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Bradon, Miss C. ALS to Violet Hunt, Oct.21, 1923; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 46)
      Durham, Dear Madame Huffer [sic]. At last I have tracked Violet Howell down: her Father was Mr. Samuel Howell [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brandt & Brandt TDS Acknowledgement of receipt of two manuscripts: "English Country" and Mr. Croyd" from Ford, Dec.6, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 47)
      New York; [Signed Carl Brandt]
    - Brandt & Brandt TD Commissions received from Brandt by Ford, [1928?-1929?]; 3 leaves (Box 49, Folder 48)
      [New York] Lists of Ford commissions 1928 and 1929]
    - Brandt & Brandt to Ford, Jan.5, 1926; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 49)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I was very sorry not to be able to see you when I was in Paris [Signed Zelma C. Brandt] [All Brandt correspondence listed by date]
    - Brandt & Brandt to William A. Bradley, Feb.1, 1926; 1 leaf + 2 leaves (Box 49, Folder 50)
      New York; Dear Mr. Bradley:- I am enclosing a copy of my letter to Mr. Ford that has just crossed [Signed Zelma C. Brandt] [Enclosed her TL to Ford of Jan.27, 1926]
    - Brandt & Brandt to TLS Ford, Mar.16, 1926; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 51)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I am so amused - but the unknown correspondent from 16 East 96th Street is Carl Brandt. [Signed Zelma Brandt]
    - Brandt & Brandt to TLS Ford, Oct.6, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 52)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I think the BEAU SABREUR synopsis is fine and one on which I think we may be able [Signed Carl Brandt]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Nov.1, 1927; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 53)
      New York; My dear Ford: Here is a copy of a letter from Collier's confirming our talk at luncheon the other day. [Signed Carl Bradt] [Included to TL[copy], of Oct. 26, 1927 of Collier's to Carl Brandt]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Dec.9, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 53)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: We have today deposited to your account $1085.00 which represents $2000.000 we received [Signed Frieda Lubelle]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Mar.23, 1928; 2 leaves (Box 49, Folder 54)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: It so happened that just after your letter to Carl came, I was seeing Mr. Woard of Jonathan Cape, [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Apr.6, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 55)
      New York; Dear Ford: I have been spending two or three weeks in the hospital for that operation [Signed Carl Brandt]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, May 19, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 56)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: As per our telephone conversation of this morning, this is to confirm [Signed Frieda Lubelle]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Jun.30, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 57)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: We have today deposited to your account our check for $100 [Signed Frieda Lubelle]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Jul3, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 58)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: You are quite right - there is $1500 due on A LITTLE LESS THAN GODS on delivery [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Aug.16, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 59)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: As you know, the office has been closed for two weeks' vacation [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Aug.22, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 60)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I do hope that you got the money that was cabled and that everything else is perfectly straight. [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt to TLS Ford, Aug.30, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 61)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: According to your instructions, I cabled you yesterday that there was approximately $700 due from Boni [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt to TLS Ford, Sept.6, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 62)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: Travel Magazine is anxious to see any travel article you may do after your trip [Signed Freda F. Holhu]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Sept.17, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 63)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: We have today deposited to your account our checks for the following: [Signed Frieda Lubelle]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Sept.18, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 64)
      New York, Dear Mr. Ford: We have today deposited to your account our check for $741.73 [Signed Frieda Lubelle]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Oct.4, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 65)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I think all money difficulties have been settled. Both the Boni and the Viking [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt TL[copy] to Harold Guinzberg, Oct.17, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 66)
      New York Dear Harold: In view of your acceptance of THAT SAME POOR MAN, the novel which was originally
    - Brandt & Brandt TL[fragment] to Ford, Oct.26, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 67)
      Dear Mr. Ford, Following up my cable to you, we have checked back the Boni statements
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Oct.29, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 68)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: We succeeded in selling the serial rights of the ENGLISH NOVEL book [Signed Nannine V. Joseph]
    - Brandt & Brandt TL[copy]S to William A. Bradley, Dec.12, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 69)
      New York Dear Mr. Bradley: Ford Madox Ford's ON TWO SUCH SILVER CURRENTS has been accepted for publication [Signed Nannine V. Joseph]
    - Brandt & Brandt TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Dec.14, 1928; 2 leaves (Box 49, Folder 70)
      New York; Dear Mr. Bradley: I do think that Mr. Ford must some how be confused about his arrangement
    - Brandt & Brandt TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Dec.17, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 71)
      New York; Dear Mr. Bradley: I cabled you this morning as follows: "CAPE OFFERS FORD TWO HUNDRED FIFTY POUNDS
    - Brandt & Brandt TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Dec.18, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 72)
      New York; Dear Mr. Bradley: As I wrote you, Mr. Horwood delivered the manuscript of Ford's novel
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Feb.21, 1929; 1 leaf + 9 leaves (Box 49, Folder 73)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: We have today deposited to your account our check for $5.10, which [Signed Frieda Lubelle] [Includes 9 leaves of Brandt statements] [Signed Frieda Lubelle]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Mar.4, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 74)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I am returning herewith your own copy and one carbon of "Honoria Mary Lelage" [Signed Nannie V. Joseph]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Mar.7, 1929; 1 leaf + 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 75)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: Below is a list of the payments made to your account at the Guaranty Trust [Signed Frieda Lubelle] [Included is TLS to Ford from Brandt & Brandt [signed by Lubelle], March 6, 1929 plus Oct. 1928 listing of royalty statement]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Apr.26, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 76)
      New York; My dear Ford: I have finished reading the new instalment of "NOTTERDAM". It's fine. [Signed Carl Brandt]
    - Brandt & Brandt to TLS Ford, May 1, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 77)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I do wish you would have a talk with Donald Freeman personally on your Vanity Fair contract. [Signed Nannine Joseph]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, May 21, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 78)
      New York Dear Mr. Ford: There is nothing that you have to do further about the bond. The Immigration Society will advise you [Signed Frieda Lubelle]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, May 27, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 79)
      New York; My dear For: I have been so busy trying to get things lined up this morning that I haven't been able to telephone you. [Signed Carl Brandt]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Jun.12, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 80)
      New York; Dear Ford: Would you consider having a limited edition of ENGLISH COUNTRY done? [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Jun.28, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 81)
      New York; Dear Ford: I called up the Dial people and they tell me definitely that the owners of the magazine [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 82)
      New York; Dear Ford: First of all, Houghton Mifflin have returned NOTTERDAM. They feel that the last part of the book needs revision. [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLSto Ford, Jul.16, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 83)
      New York; Dear Ford: Cape has cabled as follows: "Quite satisfied publish NOTTERDAM but manuscript rough [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Aug.2, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 84)
      New York; Dear Ford: The Viking Press will send me formal releases of contract, which I will forward to you [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Oct.3, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 85)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: We have to-day deposited to your account our check for $80.13, which represents the amount [Signed Frieda Lubelle]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Oct.11, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 86)
      New York; Dear Ford: The reprint sale reported by Boni was for the use of a selection from JOSEPH CONRAD [Signed Bernice Baumgarten]
    - Brandt & Brandt TL[copy]to Ford, Jan.27, 1930; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 87)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: The following is the total net amount of monies you have received
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Mar.11, 1930; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 88)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: We are returning herewith "Honoria Mary Lelage" [Signed Carl Brandt]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Apr.28, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 89)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: We have today deposited to your account our check for $5.62, which represents [Signed Frieda Lubelle]
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to William A. Bradley, Dec.30, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 90)
      New York; Dear Mr. Bradley: We are enclosing herewith a dollar draft for $21.00 which represents $22.10
    - Brandt & Brandt TLS to Ford, Mar.26, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 91)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: The J.B. Lippincott Company, the publishers of the "One Hour Library" [Signed Lillian Bassein]
    - No Box 49, Folder 92, 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 92)
      Number skipped.
    - Brentano's TLS to Ford, Apr.27, 1929; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 93)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: Here are the three books from which the prize-winning novel is to be chosen. [Signed Jacques Le Clercq] [Enclosed is leaflet "Prix Brentano"]
    - British Broadcasting Corporation TLS to Ford, Jul.3, 1935; 2 leaves (Box 49, Folder 94)
      London; Dear Mr. Ford Madox Ford, During the autumn we are proposing to broadcast a series of twelve talks [Signed Mary Adams]
    - Britton, John envelope to The Rev. James Raine, [n.d.]; 1 envelope (Box 49, Folder 95)
      [Envelope] [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Bromfield, Louis ALS to Stella Bowen, [n.d.]; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 96)
      Paris; Dear Stella:- Everyone in the family has flopped with the grippe so we've had to postpone
    - Bromfield, Louis TLS to Ford, Oct.7, 1930; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 97)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: This is just a line to say that I shall be delighted to come tomorrow
    - Bromfield, Mary M[printed, copy] "A la recherche du temps perdu", [Jan., 1943]; 6 leaves (Box 49, Folder 98)
      [Photocopy of Mary Bromfield essay from "Town and Country", January, 1943.]
    - [Brooke, Rupert?] AL[postcard] to Elsie Martindale Hueffer, Sept.28, 1908; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 99)
      Japan; Since writing you I have just rec.d your letter of Oct. 24 '07
    - Broun, Haywood Campbell TLS to Ford, Jan.4, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 49, Folder 100)
      New Canaan, Ct.; Dear Mr. Ford, We have got the crack-brained idea of having a Fiction Serial in NUTMEG, [Ford's AL reply on verso of second leaf]
    - Broun, Heywood Campbell TL to Ford, Apr.11, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 101)
      New Canaan, Ct.; My dear Ford, You know that I have succeeded to the Ownership and Management
    - Brown, Austin (Steward) AMS Account Book with Barker Esquire, Nov.,1893-Mar.,1894; 48 leaves (Box 49, Folder 102)
      [Small Account Book from Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Curtis TLS to Ford, Mar.19, 1906; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 103)
      London; Dear Sir, I am much obliged for your letter, and for the photograph of Ford Madox Brown [Verso contains AL[fragment]S to [Elsie Martindale Hueffer], signed FMFM A.]
    - Brown, Curtis TLS to Violet Hunt, Mar.12, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 104)
      London; Dear Mrs. Hueffer, Your letter of March 11 is received. Conrad seems to be getting books out faster now [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Curtis TLS to Violet Hunt, Nov.17, 1920; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 105)
      London; Dear Mrs. Hueffer, Enclosed from Nigel de Grey, manager of Messrs. William Collins Sons & Co., Ltd., explains itself. [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Curtis TLS to Violet Hunt, Nov.23, 1920; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 106)
      London; Dear Mrs. Hueffer, Your letter of November 19 surprised me a bit, for it would be inconceivable that we could [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown,m Elizabeth C ALS to Ford Madox Brown, Dec.16, 1839; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 107)
      Antwerp; My dear Ford, I dare say you have expected to hear from me before but I waited to see Mr. Slingenger [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Emma Madox ADS Will, Apr.20, 1888; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 49, Folder 108)
      London; After my Death: I request that everything I possess all property that may come by inheritance to me, {Emma was Ford's grandmother] [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Ernes Brown & Phillips TLS to Ford, Nov.2, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 49, Folder 109)
      London; Dear Mr. Ford, Messrs. Macmillan are not going to press with the book entitled "Prefaces on Art"
    - Brown, Ford ALS to Ford Madox Brown, Jan.24, 1839; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 1)
      London; My dear Fordy, As I feel myself a little better I shall try to have a few lines for you to puzzle yourself [ Ford Brown was apparently Ford Madox Brown's father] [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox Photograph, [n.d.]; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 1.5)
      Photograph "The Last of England" [Julian Loewe papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox ADS Will, [1886?]; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 2)
      This is the last Will & Testament of me Ford Madox Brown of 3 Addison Terrace, Victoria Park, Manchester [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox AL[fragment] to Emma Madox Brown, [n.d.]; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 3)
      London; Dearest Wife/ I received your dear affectionate letter last night in coming home; it is very sweet [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford MadoxALS to Emma Madox Brown, [n.d.]; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 4)
      Cheshire; Dearest Emma, I am still in bed, where they insisted I should breakfast as I have a slight cold. [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox ALS to Emma Madox Brown, Aug.5, 1870; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 50, Folder 5)
      London; Dearest Love, Just a line to say I arrived home safe some time before 1 - & found Lucy along with the new cook - [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox ALS to Emma Madox Brown, Aug.11, 1870; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 6)
      London; Dearest Love, Your communication has taken me by surprise indeed - though properly speaking it need not - only I thought [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox ALS to Emma Madox Brown, [1883?]; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 7)
      London; My dearest Emma, At home this morning I was very delighted to get your letter. Those sent to me to Paris [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox ALS to Emma Madox Brown, Aug.20, 1888; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 8)
      London; Dearest Emma, I hear from Cullingworth, as also from nurse, that your rheumatism sees not likely to last long. [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox ALS to Emma Madox Brown, Aug.5, 1889; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 9)
      London; Dearest Emma, You have almost been gone a week now & I have not written to you. [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox AL[draft?]S to Edward Burne-Jones, Feb.9, 1888; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 10)
      London; My dear Jones, I thank you much for your very kind note taking one back so vividly [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox AL to Ford, Apr.14, 1891; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 50, Folder 11)
      London; Dear Fordie, I fear you may not understand the scrawls I send you back. [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox ALS to Ford, Sept.20, 1892; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 12)
      London; Dear Fordey, Have you got Lewe's "Biography of Philosophy"? I have lost mine & Carl Thomas wishes to borrow it of me [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Brown, Ford Madox ALS to Catherine Brown Hueffer, Jun.27, 1872; 1 leaf (Box 50, Folder 13)